http://www.viatekproducts.com/pages/privacy-policy

Search
What are you looking for?
Add description and links to your promotion
Shop now
Your headline
Image caption appears here
Menu title This section doesn’t currently include any content. Add content to this section using the sidebar.
Your product's name
$49.00
Add your deal, information or promotional text
Privacy Policy
Viatek aims to provide our customers with a positive online shopping experience and we want you to know that your protection is important to us. We have taken all necessary steps in accordance with accepted industry practice to protect the security and privacy of our customers' personal information.
This privacy statement describes how Viatek collects and uses the personal information you provide on all of its owned and operated websites. The site you are visiting is owned and operated by Viatek.
It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of [our website visitors and service users]; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.
We use cookies on our website. Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of [our website and services], we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our website.
In this policy, "we", "us" and "our" refer to Viatek Consumer Products. For more information about us, see the last paragraph.
How we use your personal data
Fulfill, confirm and track your order,
Identify your product and service preferences,
Send product updates or warranty information,
Respond to inquiries and customer service requests,
Administer your account,
Improve our Website, service, product offerings, marketing and promotional efforts, and overall customer experience,
Prevent and detect fraud or abuse,
Conduct research and analysis to better understand our customer,
Display content based upon your interests,
We may process [data about your use of our website and services] ("usage data"). The usage data may include [your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your service use]. The source of the usage data is [our analytics tracking system]. This usage data may be processed [for the purposes of analysing the use of the website and services]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [monitoring and improving our website and services].
We may process [your account data] ("account data"). [ The account data may [include your name and email address] The source of the account data is [you or your employer].] The account data may be processed [for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you.] The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract].
We may process [your information included in your personal profile on our website] ("profile data"). [ The profile data may include [your name, address, telephone number, email address, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, relationship status, interests and hobbies, educational details and employment details]. The profile data may be processed for [the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of our website and services]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at you request, to enter into such a contract].
We may process [your personal data that are provided during the use of our services] ("service data"). The source of the service data is [you or your employer]. The service data may be processed [for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our databases and communicating with you]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business]] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract].
We may process [information that you post for publication on our website or through our services] ("publication data"). The publication data may be processed [for the purposes of enabling such publication and administering our website and services]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business]] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract].
We may process [information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services] ("enquiry data"). The enquiry data may be processed [for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent].
We may process [information relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information] ("customer relationship data"). [ The customer relationship data may include [your name, your employer, your job title or role, your contact details, and information contained in communications between us and you or your employer]. [ The source of the customer relationship data is [you or your employer]. The customer relationship data may be processed [for the purposes of managing our relationships with customers, communicating with customers, keeping records of those communications and promoting our products and services to customers]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper management of our customer relationships].
We may process [information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through our website] ("transaction data"). [ The transaction data may include [your contact details, your card details and the transaction details].] The transaction data may be processed [for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those transactions]. The legal basis for this processing is [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business].
We may process [information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters] ("notification data"). The notification data may be processed [for the purposes of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters]. The legal basis for this processing is [consent] OR [the performance of a contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into such a contract].
We may process [information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us] ("correspondence data"). The correspondence data may include [the communication content and metadata associated with the communication]. [Our website will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms.] The correspondence data may be processed [for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping]. The legal basis for this processing is [our legitimate interests, namely [the proper administration of our website and business and communications with users].
We may process [any of your personal data identified in this policy] where necessary for [the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure]. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely [the protection and assertion of our legal rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others].
We may process [any of your personal data identified in this policy] where necessary for [the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice]. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely [the proper protection of our business against risks].
In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section, we may also process [any of your personal data] where such processing is necessary [for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or] in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.
Please do not supply any other person's personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.
Providing your personal data to others
We may disclose [your personal data] to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy. [Information about our group of companies can be found at www.viatekproducts.com.]
We may disclose [your personal data] to [our insurers and/or professional advisers] insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of [obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure].
We may disclose personal information to [our suppliers or subcontractors] [identified at www.viatekproducts.com] insofar as reasonably necessary to process your business.
Financial transactions relating to [our website and services] [are] OR [may be] handled by our payment services providers. We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of [processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds]. You can find information about the payment services providers' privacy policies and practices at www.viatekproducts.com.
We may disclose [your enquiry data] to [one or more of those selected third party suppliers of goods and services identified on our website] for the purpose of [enabling them to contact you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or services]. [Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party's use of your personal data.]
In addition to the specific disclosures of personal data set out in this Section, we may disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.[ We may also disclose your personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.]
Amendments
We may update this policy from time to time by publishing a new version on our website.
You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.
We [may] OR [will] notify you of [changes] OR [significant changes] to this policy [by email or through the private messaging system on our website].
Your rights
In this Section 8, we have summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the rights are complex, and not all the details have been included in our summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.
Your principal rights under data protection law are:
the right to access;
the right to rectification;
the right to erasure;
the right to restrict processing;
the right to object to processing;
the right to data portability;
the right to complain to a supervisory authority; and
the right to withdraw consent.
You have the right to confirmation as to if we process your personal data and, where we do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information. That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing, the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. [You can access [your personal data] by visiting www.viatekrpoducts.com when logged into our website.]
You have the right to have any inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you completed.
In some circumstances you have the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those circumstances include: [the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed]. However, there are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where processing is necessary: [for exercising the right of freedom of expression and information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims].
In some circumstances you have the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.
You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us; or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party. If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.
You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes (including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.
You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.
To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal data is:
consent; or
that the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,
and such processing is carried out by automated means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.
If you consider that our processing of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence, your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.
To the extent that the legal basis for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness of processing before the withdrawal.
You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at dpo@viatek.com. Opting out of newsletters and marketing emails will not affect communication via email or telephone relating to your orders.
When we enable you to create a profile, and share information such as messages, photos, and videos with others, we cannot control the actions of others with whom you may choose to share your pages and information.
About cookies
A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.
Cookies may be either "persistent" cookies or "session" cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.
Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.
Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies
We collect the information we mentioned in the previous paragraphs through the use of various technologies, including cookies. A cookie is a piece of data that a Web site can send to your browser, which is then stored on your computer as an anonymous tag that identifies your computer, and in some cases, you.
Some Viatek pages use cookies, sent by Viatek, its third party vendors, or other technologies to better serve you when you return to the Website. You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You also can set your browser to turn off cookies. If you do so, however, some Websites, including ours, may not work properly. Our Viatek cookies are linked to personal information; however our third party vendor cookies only collect data in the aggregate.
We receive data from the various devices you use to access our sites. This may include location and IP information, device ID information, the pages within our site that you visit, or the type of browser you are using. We may even receive GPS information from your device so we can provide you location-based services.
Managing cookies
Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:
https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);
https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);
http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);
https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet Explorer);
https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and
https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).
Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites.
If you block cookies, you will not be able to use all the features on our website.
Security
The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Websites to your profile page to share with others within your network.
We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
Our details
This website is owned and operated by Viatek Consumer Products Group, Inc
We are registered and our registered office is at 6011 Century Oaks Drive, Chattanooga, TN 37416.
You can contact us: [by post, to [the postal address given above]];
[using our website contact form];
[by telephone, on [the contact number published on our website from time to time]]; or
[by email, using [the email address published on our website from time to time]].
Data protection officer
Our data protection officer's contact details are:
Scott Sloat
dpo@viatek.com
1-888-784-2835
